[theme music]
[woman 1 gasps]
That cake is so beautiful. It's so pretty.
- Looks like someone's about to propose.
- I know!
[gasps]
[slurping]
[woman 2] Ah…
[gentle music]
- [chef] Hey.
- [thudding]
Hey, man. Not there.
- Not here?
- [chef] No!
Those two.
Oh! Apologies.
[cart rattles]
[nervous chuckle]
Sorry.
- [woman 1] It's not them.
- [woman 2] Wow. How beautiful.
Maybe it's for you.
- [woman 3] It wasn't for her.
- [woman 4] No, it's them over there.
- [man] Let's celebrate.
- It's so pretty. What a lucky girl.
- [woman 1] Look at the ring.
- [woman 2] Beautiful.
Soo-jin, will you marry me?
- [customers cheering]
- Say you will. Say you will.
[Ha-kyung] Marriage always felt
like a natural progression for me.
Just like how the flowers bloom in spring
and the rainy season comes in summer,
it felt natural,
something that would just come.
[reporter] Summer heat is in full swing,
and the rainy season's
just around the corner.
Cloudy skies can be expected
starting this weekend
with some ongoing showers…
[Ha-kyung] However, with climate change
and the growing uncertainty
of weather forecasting nowadays…
[glasses clinking]
Why did they take a risk like that?
Huh?
[woman 1] Wow, that's so sweet.
- [man] So cool.
- Oh, uh, it's noisy in here.
- Should we leave now?
- [man] Very nice.
- [Soo-jin] I love it. Ah!
- Okay.
[Ha-kyung] What really is natural
to us anymore?
[sighs]
No way.
How could it even happen?
Those two are together?
Are you sure you're not confused about it?
I saw it with my own two eyes.
The two of them were driving around
and went in for a drink.
Well, they're on the same team.
Of course, coworkers go for drinks.
Also, what's her name? Jin Ha-kyung.
She's not his type at all.
Same thing with Ha-kyung.
She'd never go for a guy
who is that arrogant and headstrong.
That's what I'm saying.
I just don't think it makes sense
that they would be going out, huh?
[groans]
[sighs]
I'm sure that he's just, uh,
going after her
to get back at me, that bastard.
What?
Si-woo oppa is unpredictable,
but he wouldn't do something like that.
"Oppa"?
You just called that guy your oppa?
[sighs]
I misspoke. I take it back.
Anyway, that's not like Lee Si-woo.
Uh-huh. And I bet
he wouldn't do this either.
Look what he did. What he did here.
- That's because you attacked him first.
- I told you.
Never take his side over mine, didn't I?
[sighs]
[Ki-jun] What? What?
What's on your mind?
[sighs]
I'm saying those two are not dating.
So stop dragging other people
into our relationship, oppa.
- Seriously.
- Come on. He's trying to hurt me.
- [door opens]
- I'm serious! I know!
[door slams]
Uh, in the restaurant--
What should we do this weekend?
- Huh?
- We're off duty.
What do you want to do?
Ah, I don't know.
Hmm, we could see a movie.
Or, uh, that horror one
looked pretty cool, so…
Sure.
Maybe we could drive out to the suburbs.
That sounds good too.
Or do you wanna work out together?
Seems like you like to run too.
Also great.
Or we could just get
some groceries from the market.
Okay.
- You're saying okay to everything.
- Hmm?
You don't sound excited.
You're just saying yes to whatever I say.
That's because everything
really does sound good.
To be honest,
I just like walking together.
Well, I do too, yeah.
But we don't get a lot of days off,
so I want us to do something special.
So what's your preference?
Um…
There are a few options.
I want to go check out one
of those rock and roll bowling places.
And I want to go to Jeju Island for--
Let's forget that. There will be
too many newlyweds there
this time of the year.
What's wrong with newlyweds?
I don't know.
It's suffocating?
What do you mean?
That, uh, whole thing of marriage
being the end goal, it's not always right.
When I see married people acting
like now, it's all happily ever after.
Well, it's different for everyone.
But still, I just feel
a little suffocated.
Oh, hang here.
I'll go get us some cold drinks.
- Hmm.
- Okay.
[pensive music]
EPISODE 9
DRY CHANGMA (RAINY SEASON)
INNOVATIVE WEATHER SERVICES
A STEPPING STONE TO PUBLIC SAFETY
A stationary front has currently formed
over the southern Jeju Sea.
It seems like it will start raining
in Jeju early tomorrow now.
The stationary front is moving
along about how we expected at 35km/h.
- Thirty-five kilometers?
- Yes.
[Bong-chan] Judging
by the current situation in the air,
rainfall will start in the metro area
tomorrow evening as expected.
- [Ha-kyung] That's right, sir.
- [Bong-chan] Hmm.
- How about the press?
- Uh, yes.
Because of the heat wave,
the rainy season
has everyone very excited.
I see.
Okay, good.
We'll give the press the briefing
as planned. Let's move on.
Yes, sir. Hello, Jeju Office?
[light music]
[Bong-chan] All right.
Great job, everyone.
[all] Thank you!
NATIONAL METEOROLOGICAL CENTER
COMPREHENSIVE CONTROL SYSTEM
May I have a word with you?
[sighs]
Are you dating Lee Si-woo?
What?
Am I dating who?
I saw everything. I saw you together.
The place I told you
that's a good spot to go have a drink.
The Izakaya, I saw you two.
[comical music]
Ah, that night.
[chuckles]
Lee Si-woo and I are teammates.
Can't a couple of teammates
go for a drink?
- That looks like dating to you, huh?
- Nu-uh.
Your mouth on his
is what looks like dating.
[laughs]
What? Come on!
[sighs]
You've really changed, Jin Ha-kyung.
When we dated, you used to hate showing
any affection when others were around.
And now you're out there going around
kissing Lee Si-woo
where the whole bar can see you.
You… I should have known since that day.
When I was fighting with him,
I thought it was weird you left together,
so I followed to see where you went.
You were having a real moment.
[scoffs]
Then…
Am I supposed to do nothing
if my subordinates get beat up
by some psycho?
A psycho who I was involved with
in the past?
- "Psycho"?
- What of it, huh?
Why would I ever want to date
in the workplace again
after what you and I went through?
Are you crazy?
- What--
- [Ha-kyung] Also…
Why do you even care
who I'm kissing or making out with?
[sighs]
- Hey!
- What?
I'm scared for you, 'kay?
Men know what men can do.
Lee Si-woo is not a decent guy.
Also, I didn't want to bring this up.
But do you even know what kind of scene
he made at my wedding with Yu-jin?
Ah, so you broke off our wedding
with everything planned
to marry another woman
because you're such a good guy?
Oh, gosh, look, okay?
Yu-jin gave me no choice.
That bastard is just trying to get
his revenge on me through you.
Oh, so you're just really concerned,
then, huh?
Of course, I'm concerned.
The only thing you're scared off
is your name getting dragged
through the dirt
if I go out with Lee Si-woo.
Well, of course, yeah, that too.
Be honest. Wouldn't you be scared of that?
- Hey!
- What?
Go to hell.
[comical music]
Ha-kyung, you can't do this!
Ha-kyung, hey!
[sighs]
She's got no sense at all.
[inhales deeply]
[tense music]
[sighs]
It's revenge! I'm serious!
[groans]
[playful music]
[grunts]
[humming gleefully]
[chuckles, taps]
Aren't you excited for the weekend, huh?
Of course.
It's my first weekend in forever.
I can't ever see anybody
on a weekday when I'm off.
It's so lonely.
[sighs]
I wish I could have
a little loneliness on my day off.
Just kids. Kids all the time,
whenever I get a weekend.
And if they've got study sessions,
I have to take them back
and forth all over town.
I'd rather be right here.
Mm.
I already know what Mr. Um's gonna do.
What are you doing tomorrow, Mr. Lee?
I've got a date, so…
[Si-woo] I heard that a good play opened.
Oh, I love theater. What show is it?
Oh, uh… What was it?
[message received tone]
- [Ha-kyung] Emergency.
- "Emergency"?
[Soo-jin] "Emergency"?
- Oh, the show?
- Huh?
Oh, uh, it's a musical at a small theater.
Oh, a small theater.
- [keyboard clacking]
- [Si-woo] What is it?
And you, Mr. Shin? Your weekend?
Well, a weekend off
doesn't change anything.
- First, when I get up, I make a coffee.
- [Soo-jin] Hmm.
[Ha-kyung] Han Ki-jun is onto us.
[Si-woo] How?
[Ha-kyung] He saw us together
at the Izakaya that day.
[Si-woo] So what did you say?
[indistinct chatter]
[Ha-kyung] I denied it, of course.
[Seok-ho] For breakfast,
I usually have a simple salad.
Work out and try
and clean up around the house.
[Si-woo] Or maybe
why don't we just come clean?
[Ha-kyung] We have to keep denying it.
[Seok-ho] I eat the food when it comes.
And after lunch, I put on a record…
[Ha-kyung] Let's not go
to Daehangno tomorrow.
[Si-woo] Why not?
[Ha-kyung] There's a maeundalgbaljib place
Ki-jun really likes there.
He goes there sometimes,
so I think tomorrow is too risky.
[Seok-ho] …classical pianists have
different brain structures.
Actually…
[Si-woo] It wasn't easy
to get those tickets.
Should we go for a jog near Hangang, then?
[Seok-ho] When they need a jazz pianist…
[Ha-kyung] No. We shouldn't
go outside at all for a while.
[keyboard clacking]
[Si-woo] We can't just stay home.
[Seok-ho] The biggest difference was that
the jazz pianists showed
high reactive brains
and the classical pianists
showed high accuracy.
- [sighs]
- It's fascinating.
They're both interesting, depending
on the perfect opportunity to focus on.
Their brainwaves have
physical reactions differently.
So maybe it's the same for us?
We're all forecasters,
but for digital forecasters…
CONTINUOUS HEAT WAVE…
JIN HA-KYUNG?
[Ki-jun] Yu-jin, do you know
who Lee Si-woo is dating right now?
Who is he dating?
Jin Ha-kyung.
[sighs]
Makes no sense.
- What?
- Huh?
- [Eun-ji] What makes no sense?
- Nothing, I'm good.
MOTHER-IN-LAW
[phone vibrates]
[vibrating continues]
[deep exhale]
Hi, mother. How are you?
[giggles]
Sorry?
Ah. Oh, so sorry. Um, I forgot.
Uh, yes, I'll tell Ki-jun.
Okay.
Well, I'll see you this weekend.
Yes.
[sighs]
- [Eun-ji] Where are you going?
- Uh, shopping errand.
"Shopping"?
- [elevator dings]
- [automated voice] Door is opening.
[phone vibrates]
- [automated voice] Door is closing.
- Hey, eonni.
[Tae-kyung] Mom said you should drop by
on your way home today.
Um, I'm busy.
She's going to go to your place
if you don't come over here.
- I'm sure she will--
- [Dong-han] Si-woo.
What should we do for dinner?
- Budaejjigae sounds good.
- [Dong-han] You know how to make it?
- Okay. I'll be right there.
- No. I know how to order it, though.
- That's strange.
- What? She's not coming here?
- She's on her way.
- Huh?
Ma.
Are you really gonna confront Ha-kyung?
Just leave her alone.
That is not what parents do.
[sighs]
- [Si-woo] What else should we add?
- [indistinct chatter]
- [Dong-han] Dumplings.
- [Si-woo] Dumplings? All right.
- Yeah, and we have ramen at home.
- We do have ramen.
Ooh, we're gonna order, uh, budaejjigae.
Is there anything we should add to that?
Uh, well, I got to go to my mom's house,
so you two enjoy dinner.
Your mom's?
- Is something, uh…
- I don't know.
You know the school trip
I need for credit?
[Bo-mi] Where should I go this time?
[Hyang-rae] Where are you?
[Dong-han] At the KMA, like always.
He's not here. He left a while ago.
Where on earth
has he been sleeping these days?
Mom?
Huh?
It's okay. I can handle it.
[chuckles]
- What is it?
- The school trip.
I have one idea.
[Soo-ja] Go on just three blind dates
that I arranged.
That's my final wish.
Come on, Ha-kyung. Just do it.
I said no from the start.
Am I supposed to throw away money
for nothing?
What about my time, huh?
Should I throw that out?
That's the reason I said
only three dates and no more.
Who knows? Maybe on one of those,
you'll meet the man for you.
These days, they say couples
who met this way
get divorced far less than those
who just met through dating.
[scoffs]
Why look at me?
[Soo-ja] Passion and drama?
All of that's no good at all.
Just look at Tae-kyung.
They acted like
they'd die without each other,
and then one year
after the wedding, divorce.
Mom, why do you always say that?
It's about her, not me!
[door slides open]
Don't try and wait
to pay me respect once I'm gone.
There's still time for that now, huh?
[Soo-ja] While I'm living.
[playful music]
[crickets chirping]
[Soo-ja] You cold-hearted brat!
It's the last wish
of your old mother, huh?
Is it really that hard?
How can you just say no?
- Listen!
- [banging on table]
How can you just strike me down
without the slightest hesitation, huh?
Huh?
I'm sick of always hearing about marriage.
What? Are they arresting singles?
Oh! Oh! That little…
- I'm leaving.
- You're being too harsh.
You know she's just acting like that
'cause she's frustrated.
You and I are the only kids she has.
Her eldest came crawling to her,
a failed wife, and her youngest…
She just wants to know that
you and I'll have someone to lean on
when she goes.
Come on, that's all she wants.
Well, then, Mom can remarry.
Oh! Or you could.
Hey, watch your manners.
Do you know how I feel
every time it goes like this?
I feel like I'm being pushed
to the edge of a cliff.
And how come it always feels that way?
It makes me feel so angry.
Yeah. You got a point.
Anyway, I… I feel awful. I'm heading out.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sighs]
[mellow music]
[sharp exhale]
[Tae-kyung] Ma.
Were you happy
when you and Dad were together?
Why would you go and ask me that
out of nowhere?
There's not one marriage that's just good.
Sometimes it's simple.
And sometimes it's not.
Despite that, two is better than one,
and three is much better than two.
You know Mi-jeong.
Her daughter would use to say
she'd live alone forever.
But look now.
Now she's got a great life.
A husband and kids too.
And her husband's got a good job.
[inhales sharply]
But you have to understand
Ha-kyung's not the same as her.
Maybe living alone really works for her.
What?
Well, it's worth considering at least.
Go to bed. All that yelling this evening
must have tired you out.
[grunts]
[mellow music]
Oh, hey.
Hey.
Your mom called today.
She wants to have dinner with us tomorrow.
You're free, aren't you?
Did you go shopping again?
- Oh, uh, that's--
- Must be nice to be so carefree.
I thought we were saving money
'cause of our lease.
We can afford the deposit
for the new place thanks to the loan.
But you know it's not cheap to move
and there's still a lot to take care of.
Are you saying that I'm just
thoughtlessly spending our money?
If you were being rational,
you wouldn't have spent
our money like it's nothing.
Oppa.
Forget about it.
It'll just become a fight if we talk.
I gotta shower.
- [door opens]
- [sighs]
[door closes]
[sighs]
[phone vibrates]
[Si-woo] Is something going on at home?
[gentle music]
[Ha-kyung] Yeah.
But you don't have to worry about it.
[Si-woo] If you're tired,
I'm fine with just chilling
at the apartment tomorrow.
Will you look out the living room
in a second?
Want a beer?
[comical music]
Uh, no, all for you.
- [chuckles]
- Mm-hmm.
[sighs]
[grunts]
[sucks teeth]
[Si-woo] Yeah, staying here
is not really an option.
Is it?
[Ha-kyung] Let's just avoid
crowded places.
A place where it's less crowded
when it rains.
Can you think of a place like that?
[Si-woo] There is one place
I can think of.
- [Ha-kyung] Where?
- [Si-woo] Do you like nature?
[Ha-kyung] Of course.
[Si-woo] Can you stand
a little inconvenience?
[Ha-kyung] I guess.
[Si-woo] Okay, then.
Where are we going?
[chuckles]
[exhales]
[giggles]
What are you doing, huh?
[playful music]
[car engine shuts off]
[Ki-jun] You're off work today, right?
I need to talk to you.
Meet me at the brunch café
in front of the apartment when you get up.
I'll be waiting.
[sighs]
[birds chirping]
Hmm?
[mischievous music]
Morning.
- Lee Si-woo.
- [car door closes]
- [Ha-kyung] Thanks for waiting
- Shall we?
What? Director and subordinate together?
You two are busted.
[engine starts]
[upbeat music]
Where the hell are they going?
[Ki-jun sighs]
[groans]
[phone vibrates]
HONEY
[Yu-jin] Where are you? You didn't forget
that we're visiting your mom, right?
We need to leave before six,
so be home by then.
- All right. I got time. I got time.
- [phone clacks]
Traffic looks lighter.
- So where are we going?
- We're almost there.
[exhales]
I hope you'll enjoy it.
[chill upbeat music]
- Thank you.
- It's right up there.
- [Si-woo] Thank you.
- You're welcome.
[intriguing music]
[car door opens]
- [splattering]
- What?
[groans]
Who let their dog…
- [Ki-jun] You little…
- [whines]
- Oh, jeez.
- [shoe squeaking]
[phone vibrating]
HONEY
[upbeat music]
This is so nice.
[pants]
[Si-woo] I'm so glad we came here.
Here, I'll help with that.
- [Ki-jun grunts]
- No, it's okay.
[groans]
[moans in pain]
- [sighs]
- [line ringing]
How come he's ghosting me all of a sudden?
[sighs]
[line ringing]
[exhales sharply]
[operator] The person you are trying
to reach is not available at this time.
[scoffs]
[sighs]
[Ha-kyung] We're here
at Camp Site Letter B.
So we need to go that way.
Oh, that's a long walk.
- Oh, it's no problem. Let's go.
- Okay.
- [Ha-kyung] Can I help?
- [Si-woo] No, thanks.
- [Ha-kyung] Are you sure?
- [Si-woo] Yeah.
Let's go.
I'll hop on. You're so strong.
Are you riding it? Then I'll push.
I'll make irrefutable evidence
when I confront them.
Uh… Uh…
Where is it?
All right. I got time. I got time. Yeah.
Ah!
[grumbles]
What do I do?
[snoring]
[grunts, clears throat]
[clears throat]
[grunts]
Hmm…
[yawns]
[light knocks]
Did she go out?
Si-woo, you had breakfast yet?
Hmm. How about we go get, um…
[sighs]
Where is everyone?
[tongue clicks]
[sighs]
[light music]
MOBILE DISASTER PREVENTION
AND WEATHER SYSTEM
NO CONNECTION
That's weird. I can't get a signal.
Internet's not working?
Yeah.
They definitely said it would.
It'd be great to at least see
the live reporting.
Hang on a second.
[line dials, rings]
- [Seok-ho] Hey.
- Hello.
Could you check
the current situation on the live radar?
You can do it yourself.
I'm outside and I don't have any internet.
Just do it for a friend?
[sighs]
You have to be joking. Wait a second.
What's…
Oh, he's going over to…
Let me see your phone.
Right now, the stationary front
is moving northward Jeju 5mm of rain.
And it's barely drizzling
on the south coast.
Okay.
[Si-woo] It's drizzling in Jeju
and the southern region.
[Si-woo] Just a second, Seok-ho.
[Ha-kyung] Also ask
for the NWP model from 1:00 p.m.
Oh, the NWP model too?
[quirky music]
Who are you with right now?
With my girlfriend.
[chuckles]
Then forget about this stuff
and just enjoy your date.
Team One's in the office, and I'll keep
an eye on the live situation.
- [Seok-ho] I'm hanging up.
- Okay.
[phone beeps]
What did he say?
He said there's lots of people at the KMA,
so I should focus on what I'm doing.
I know that already. I'm just curious.
[Si-woo] Seok-ho is right.
We need to relax, so we can be rested.
The stationary front
is heading north as expected.
So just forget it.
Let's focus on each other.
Okay.
[water running]
- [Si-woo] This, then?
- [Ha-kyung] Yeah.
[breathing deeply]
[sighs]
Okay.
Right.
Team One will take care of it.
Okay, forget it. All right.
[Seok-ho] One vanilla latte, please.
Some soy milk, please.
And just two pumps of syrup. No more.
- [machine beeping]
- I'll use my free one.
- What's your name?
- It's Shin Seok-ho.
There's no card.
What do you mean there's no card?
I just got my last…
- From who?
- I don't know. A staff member.
Yeah. I'm getting a coffee first.
When our manager comes in,
she can check for you, okay?
Can you just pay for it now?
So you're saying
my punch card is lost now?
I let you people keep it
because you said it would be safe.
Oh, 1302?
Other customers are waiting right now.
Right, how about we check one more time?
Hello.
Oh, what brings you here?
This is a coffee shop.
I'm here for coffee.
Right.
What about you? What… what's going on?
[sighs]
They lost my card
with all 12 stamps on it.
The one they stored?
As I was saying, he must understand
we can't confirm the stamps right now.
I'll look into this
when my manager arrives, okay?
So, please, for now, if you could pay--
I didn't bring my wallet
because I had a full card.
- So should I cancel your order, then?
- Ridiculous.
- Here, you can put it on this one.
- No, you don't have to.
I owe you from the other day.
What's your order?
A vanilla latte, some soy milk,
and just two pumps of syrup, no more.
Ah! Okay, that. And I'll have
a cold, iced Americano, please.
You can put his on here.
[sighs]
- Um…
- [machine beeping]
So saying "cold, iced Americano,"
that's redundant, see,
because if they make it with ice,
it has to be cold, so…
[indistinct chatter]
[sighs]
- Don't you think that I'd know that?
- Right.
- Oh, and thank you.
- Okay.
Mm, thanks.
Go ahead.
- [woman] One chamomile tea, please.
- [machine beeps]
[car engine rumbles]
No, wait! Hold on! Hey!
Hey, my car!
My car! My car!
[Ki-jun] Hey! Wait! Stop
Hey!
What?
It's bothering me.
[Si-woo] It will rain, right?
Don't you think so?
Of course. Look how gray the clouds are.
It'll rain.
[sharp exhale]
[birds chirping]
[quirky music]
Hey.
I know you're curious too.
Well, then, let's try something.
Hand me your phone.
Okay. Whoever takes their phone first
does the dishes.
Sure, but…
[inhales deeply]
…shouldn't we cook something
before we worry about the dishes?
Camping requires barbecue.
- All right. Yeah.
- [plastic rustling]
- [Si-woo humming]
- What you got?
Huh?
- [rustling]
- Huh? What?
Why, what is it?
Meat. I definitely put it in here.
[rustling]
[playful music]
- [Ha-kyung] It's okay.
- [sighs]
Camping always needs kimchi-jjigae.
We don't have anything for the broth.
Should I go get some beef
from the store over there?
All we need for kimchi-jjigae is kimchi.
- [giggles]
- [birds chirping]
[Ha-kyung] It's okay.
["Melting" by Cheeze playing]
- How is it, uh, looking?
- [Ha-kyung] It's okay.
- Is it good?
- I don't know.
I haven't tasted it.
- Wow, you're good at this.
- Okay, try it.
- Try it?
- Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
- Very good.
- Is it good?
Here, try it.
- Hmm?
- Wow, I think I'm a genius.
- It's so good.
- Stay. Oh, oh, hold it.
[chuckling]
VEHICLES SUBJECT TO FINES AND TOWS
[groans]
[phone ringing]
HONEY
- [Ki-jun] Hey.
- Where are you?
- Oh, uh, Yu-jin…
- I'll go straight to your mom's place.
I'll see you there, okay?
You have to hurry.
[somber music]
[Yu-jin] Where are you coming from?
And why are you so ragged?
It's a long story.
Did you forget what day it was?
Your mom's birthday.
You're so… cold-hearted.
"Your mom"? Really?
She's your mother-in-law, okay?
You should call her "Mom."
She called two days ago to make sure
that we could have dinner with her.
[Yu-jin] Where were you all day?
Do you know how awkward
it was alone with her?
Did she say something to you again?
Okay, I asked where you were!
I'm old enough to go places
without your permission.
Come on. I had something important
I had to check out.
- And now…
- [sighs]
Please don't say
you saw Jin Ha-kyung again.
[sighs]
You said you couldn't believe
that Ha-kyung and that ass are dating.
So she's just so important for you?
So much so you forgot your mom's birthday?
I don't know what to do.
When I ended my engagement
with her and married you,
do you know how much crap people gave me?
They said I betrayed a woman
who'd stuck with me through thick and thin
and that I'm a shameless cheat
who bailed at the last second.
I had to go through all of that.
I can't let her get away
with playing the victim
when she's dating that bastard Lee Si-woo!
[Yu-jin] Oppa.
I really wish you'd focus on our problems.
We have so much stuff
we need to fix together.
I know.
But I have to take care of this first
before I can focus
on anything else, Yu-jin.
So what will you do?
Expose them to the whole world, huh?
So what if I want to?
[scoffs]
You don't think
that people will be talking about us too
if that got out?
Why is it that you won't consider that?
[sighs]
[exhales sharply]
[Yu-jin] Be honest.
I think you not wanting her
to play the victim is a cover.
Aren't you just jealous of them
now that they're going out?
"Jealous"?
[Ki-jun] Me? Of Lee Si-woo?
Why would I be?
You're the one who would know that.
[sighs]
I…
[breathing heavily]
[crickets chirping]
[Ha-kyung] It's not raining.
I know.
It's not going to, is it?
Probably not.
What's the time?
It's going on 8:21.
We're screwed.
[chuckles]
Cheers.
[Si-woo] Cheers.
INNOVATIVE WEATHER SERVICES
A STEPPING STONE TO PUBLIC SAFETY
[pensive music]
[sighs]
Hmm…
It's been over ten minutes
since the meeting started.
- [shushes]
- Okay.
I thought we saw the NWP
had moved northward.
Hmm? Then why isn't it raining?
The Okhotsk's anticyclone
is abnormally strong
and the cold air
in the north isn't moving,
so the northing of the stationary front
is being delayed.
Isn't that the point that Mr. Um said
in our meeting before this, you know?
[Seok-ho] Yeah.
When is it going to rain?
Right now, we're looking
at the start of next week.
However, if this weather continues,
we can't rule out the chance of it
taking even longer.
[sighs]
[breathes deeply]
[Bong-chan] Okay, then.
PR should distribute explanations
to the press
about why the rain has been delayed.
And forecasting…
[sighs]
…should stay focused on the live charts.
[all in unison] Yes, sir.
Wouldn't it be better if we mention
the possibility of a drier rainy season?
- "Drier rainy season"?
- [Ki-jun] Yes.
We can't do that
when the stationary front is still active.
Even if it just stays cloudy
but doesn't rain,
I don't think it's right to just rush
an announcement like that
when rainfall's still likely.
[scoffs]
Isn't hasty conclusions
what you love? What?
Your special sense isn't working so well
right now?
Those senses are based on data
and the flow of the weather.
Either it's right or it's not.
We can't publish vague warnings
just because we're afraid
of the criticism.
"Publish vague warnings"?
Isn't that what you were saying?
Issue a statement?
[tense music]
[indistinct murmuring]
Please stop. Both of you.
No, you go on.
Huh?
[Bong-chan] Please continue.
Why don't you two gentlemen
debate it together?
And then you can draw a joint conclusion.
And we'll release the explanation material
to the news as a result of your findings.
[Bong-chan] That would be great, right?
Right?
Is there a problem?
Uh, no, Director. We'll debate.
[Bong-chan] Great. Carry on.
[Bong-chan sighs]
[indistinct chatter]
Um, Director…
I'm heading to that meeting.
Will you survive?
Yes.
[chuckles]
[phone ringing]
[intriguing music]
[breathes deeply]
[tense music]
Let's start with analyzing
why the last forecast was wrong.
I thought we were gonna work
on the reasons
why the rainy season delay happened.
I think we'd have to go back
to the forecast
and find out what we missed,
so we can explain the difference
between our prediction and what occurred.
All right, sure. Where should we start?
[remote beeps]
[Ki-jun] In the first set of forecast,
you predicted the stationary front
would cause a rainfall starting
in the Jeju area and the rest
of the southern region.
Where did this conclusion originate?
Considering the gale
of 100 hectopascals north of the front,
and how fast the North Pacific anticyclone
is expanding,
there was a high chance
that rain clouds would follow.
You think those two
are gonna take a while?
Oh, yeah.
Haven't you heard anything about why
the explanation's going on for so long?
They want to expand it.
[sighs]
[breathing deeply]
[Si-woo] Look, I'm right about this.
If you look over here,
this area is too strong for it to rise.
- Hey, Mr. Lee.
- I'm right.
- And it's too warm…
- Listen to me.
The reason this front can move up here
is because of this huge anticyclonic belt.
That's why this can't go down.
You're still missing this whole big one.
Just look at this, will you?
[inaudible]
[techno music]
- Hello.
Where is Forecaster Lee?
Oh, he's…
in the Spokesman's Office,
discussing the press release.
I think he said he would send you
an email about your work today.
Ah, here it is. Uh-huh.
Okay.
- Great work.
- You too.
Great work.
Hey, don't worry.
- [automated voice] Door is closing.
- They're not gonna fight again.
[Dong-han chuckles]
Let's all go get some dinner.
- Sure.
- Okay.
- [Myung-ju] How about something cold?
- [Dong-han] Like what?
So it was the wrong call to predict
that the stationary front
would move northward
based on the trough
in central-northern China and the gale.
[pen thudding]
Anyone would have come
to the same conclusions in the moment.
Mr. Um's theory that the stationary front
would come down was reasonable.
Still, the probability was low.
You always say that you
go off your gut feelings.
But then you blame it all on the data
when your forecast is bad.
To me, that looks like
a pretty lame excuse.
I wasn't sure.
I couldn't risk it on feelings alone.
'Cause too many people's lives
depended on us.
Someone said that to me.
[pensive music]
Then tell me why are you going
and risking it all with Ha-kyung?
She looks tough,
but she's a soft soul inside.
The way I already hurt her
was painful enough.
We should focus on the release.
If you're seeing her because you have
some negative feelings
about me or my wife…
Stop, it's not too late.
Ha-kyung doesn't do anything carelessly.
If she really started something with you,
then she's being sincere.
And if she gets hurt again,
there's a chance she won't ever
be able to recover.
Don't you think it's really
not your place to say so
when you're the one that hurt her?
I know that.
I know I seriously hurt her.
That's the reason I'm worried for her.
[somber music]
Don't worry about that, then.
I'm also the type of person
who doesn't start things if I'm not sure.
We can use this as the release.
I'll be going now.
[papers rustling]
But you should know…
See you next week, Seong-jun.
[Seong-jun] Okay, good night.
[button clicks]
[uneasy music]
[sighs]
Why…
did you break up with him?
What?
Honestly, even to me,
he seems like a good guy.
[Ki-jun] No.
Si-woo is a good guy.
Why leave a guy like that
for someone like me?
[book thuds]
You really don't know?
No.
I'm asking because I really don't.
You asked me for my hand.
You were the first.
You were the first guy
who wanted to marry me.
Not just go out. You were.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
Too bad for you.
The man you married is flat-out broke.
That's why you won't register
our marriage.
[breathes deeply]
Why are you so twisted around?
Do you really think I'd hold up filing
'cause of something like that?
Well, what then?
You never really focused on the issues
between the two of us once we got married.
You were always so focused on what
others would think about all of it.
And now, you're in a crisis because
Jin Ha-kyung might be dating Lee Si-woo
so even now,
you're focused on someone else.
How can I file it if I don't know
if you really love me anymore?
I don't know where we are.
Don't make some excuse about it.
It's all the same thing.
Oppa, stop running around all the time!
If you love me, focus!
[sighs]
[door opens]
[door slams]
[sighs]
[door lock beeping]
[Si-woo chuckles]
Oh.
Did you and Ki-jun have a run-in again?
[exhales]
I want to do better.
- What?
- Huh?
The stationary front.
- Let's analyze it again.
- Why?
Is there an unusual signal or something?
No, I discovered this when I was working
on the report with Director Han earlier.
Here.
The Okhotsk Sea air mass
that was abnormally developing
isn't expanding anymore.
And there's vapor coming in
from the southwest.
Isn't it still too weak for
the North Pacific anticyclone to start?
- What do you think?
- I agree with you.
Uh, look at this part over here.
The rain particles get stronger
as it rises, don't they?
Hmm. I'm not so sure.
If the anticyclone on the Okhotsk Sea
stops developing
and vapor keeps coming in
from the southwest,
the North Pacific anticyclone will expand.
And if all that's true,
I'd say it's two days till rain.
[light music]
Let's go with Mr. Lee's thoughts
this time.
It's true that the southwest
shows a lot of vapor right now.
Well, okay, then. Okay.
[chuckles]
Thank you for, uh, believing me.
[sighs]
INNOVATIVE WEATHER SERVICES
A STEPPING STONE TO PUBLIC SAFETY
[birds chirping]
[foreboding music]
[sighs]
THE KMA'S WEATHER FORECAST
IS WRONG AGAIN
[sighs]
THE FORECAST IS WRONG AGAIN
WHAT IS THE PROBLEM?
[breathes deeply]
The KMA's forecast was wrong yet again.
Why do you think that is?
Global warming's speeding up,
and we see this with El Niño and La Niña.
And the variables of forecasting
grow more complicated.
Could you please put that
in simpler terms?
In short, the climate is a car
ignoring all traffic lights
and we're trying to guess
which way it's going to go.
[keyboards clacking]
The reporters are loving this.
Also, because no big stuff's happened
for a while.
[Myung-ju] Poor Ms. Jin.
She's been suffering
ever since they made her director.
Nothing's working out for her.
[sighs]
[somber music]
[Ha-kyung] Aren't you tired?
Let's go in now.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have insisted.
We wouldn't have gotten it wrong.
You didn't get it wrong.
And it's not like
Mr. Um and I were right either.
You said it yourself.
Weather is a variability.
One tiny factor sometimes gets
to change the whole scene.
What are we gonna do?
Take our licks as we were wrong.
[keyboard clacking]
THE KMA'S ERRONEOUS FORECAST
[reporter] The KMA has forecast a rainfall
of 50 to 100mm an hour in Seoul, Gyeonggi,
Yeongseo and Gangwon,
starting early this morning.
But currently, most areas
are only cloudy with no rain.
Although we did avoid
a rainy morning commute today,
many are complaining that they are tired…
Bo-mi, I have a bit
of a headache right now.
- Can you…
- Okay.
- The KMA's forecast was wrong yet again.
- Wait.
[reporter] Why do you think that is?
Global warming's speeding up,
and we see this with El Niño and La Niña.
And the variables of forecasting
grow more complicated.
In short, the climate
is a car ignoring all traffic lights
and we're trying to guess
which way it's going to go.
- That sounds like a very difficult task.
- You know that woman?
- Yeah.
- Shouldn't your supercomputers
with their vast amount of accumulated data
be able to account
for all those variables?
[reporter] Thank you.
You said weather's harder to predict
'cause climate change
has increased so rapidly of late.
Shouldn't something be done about that?
Well, that's the reason we have the NWP,
so we can have more predictive power.
[exhales]
So there's no clear fix for it?
Well, we'll try our very best.
[Yu-jin] Trying is easy.
What's hard is doing your job well.
[sighs]
Is this over?
- Yes.
- Well, thank you.
I heard that you're dating Si-woo.
Did Han Ki-jun say that?
I told him it's not the truth.
[smacks lips]
Well, he is charming.
[Yu-jin] Innocent but intelligent.
He's penniless, but at least
he has some self-confidence.
And he's not hard on the eyes either.
Can I ask you a question?
Why break up with such
a good man like Si-woo?
Is it because of his father?
[scoffs]
You think you know everything, huh?
Si-woo's father, I know he's sleazy.
But not so bad
that I would break up with him for it.
Then why…
Si-woo oppa…
doesn't want marriage.
[dramatic music]
He has no intention of marrying anyone.
[button clicks]
[Ki-jun] Oh, you should know.
Ha-kyung doesn't date just anybody
unless there's a chance of marriage.
You are aware of that, right?
[sighs deeply]
- [elevator dings]
- [automated voice] Door is opening.
Going up.
[button clicks]
[Soo-ja] Uh, wait for me.
- Oh!
- [button clicks]
Hello.
[Ha-kyung] The same way
flowers bloom in spring
and the rainy season comes in summer,
marriage always felt
like a natural progression for me.
However, with climate change
and the growing uncertainty
of weather forecasting nowadays…
Si-woo oppa…
doesn't want marriage.
He has no intention of marrying anyone.
[Ha-kyung] What really is natural
to us anymore?
["Abnormal Climate" by Giriboy playing]
[Ha-kyung] I hadn't considered it
really till now,
not getting married after dating.
Who are you? My daughter lives here.
- Oh?
- Uh…
All of you are living together
because of your work?
[Soo-ja] In the elevator,
there was a man you were talking to.
How exactly does he know you?
Thanks.
Are you an only child?
Why are you asking me?
What's with the temperature in Yeouido?
Take it down now and put a blink up
on the weather portal.
[Ki-jun] The error on the disaster
prevention portal,
you tipped him off, didn't you?
You should have submitted
a report to me right away!